"Previously on The Mentalist..."
"I can't do this anymore."
You can't keep pulling me
from the path of oncoming trains.
There's new trains coming
every day.
You have information
about the case?
My brother does. Gabriel.
He's a psychic.
There's a thing inside you.
"Your cure will come
with the number three."
I didn't know where you were.
- You knew I'd be back.
- No, I didn't.
There's a serial killer
"with an evil heart
and an appetite to kill."
I saw that the killer
is going to kill again. Tonight.
"Why would the killer care
if Gabriel was a real psychic?"
"He wants one for some reason
and Gabriel didn't pass the test."
- "Could you just take a look?"
- "He was sitting in the car, right?"
The whole time I was putting out
the trash
he just sat there, staring at me.
They still haven't caught that guy
who killed those people.
It could be him. You don't know.
Serial killers don't sit in cars.
They lurk in the shadows.
Be right back.
Hey.
Stupid drunk.
Oh!
Susan!
Soos?
"What is this?"
Did you buy me another horse?
- Just a little further.
- Okay.
Is this a trick?
- Breathe that air in.
- Okay, I'm breathing in that air.
And... voilà.
Jane... what is this?
It's a little shack that I'm gonna renovate
make some additions.
We both knew things had to change.
I-I couldn't make you quit,
and I need something to do.
- So you're gonna build us a house.
- That's right.
And when I'm done, if nothing else
we have a place to live.
It's a start.
So you're gonna work here, not...
not at the FBI.
- You're quitting.
- Maybe. I-I don't know.
I haven't decided yet.
What?
I'm glad you got it. I am.
But...
I have needs, too.
Like what?
I need to know
that you're not gonna run away again.
I won't.
I need to know
that you're committed to this, to us.
I-I am. That's why I wanna do this.
Okay.
Then are you gonna take off
your wedding ring?
It just, it seems like
you don't wanna let go of it.
- No, it's not that.
- I-I understand why it's difficult for you.
- It-it's just that I'm used to it.
- I know. It...
What's up, boss?
"Sorry, Lisbon.
I know you're on your way home."
"But I need you to turn around."
We have another one.
The victim's name is Susan Herman.
Her husband reported her
missing last night.
Apparently, the killer snatched
her off her porch.
- That's a change.
- The pattern's the same otherwise...
Shot in the chest,
one fingernail ripped off.
He didn't bother hiding the body.
Could mean he's getting bolder.
Or more playful.
- Playful?
- Well, sure.
He knows we're on to him.
That's why he left her out for us to find.
- He's also done something else.
- What?
I'm not sure.
Uh, excuse me.
That mark on her left arm...
is that a puncture wound?
Looks like it.
- Is that from a needle?
- Uh, little bigger.
Could be from an IV line.
Why would he put an IV In her?
Uh, he's not poisoning them.
I don't think he was putting anything in.
More likely, he was taking something out.
Could be right. Position the body correctly
you can take out a cup or more
of blood with an IV.
So he kills them, rips out a fingernail
and takes a cup of blood.
And we're making every possible effort.
Thanks. All right, thanks for calling.
Everyone and his sister wants to know
when we're making an arrest.
Right. This is Rick Tork
from the Santa Fe office.
He's gonna help out
while we're short-handed.
Hey.
Dennis Abbott. Thanks for coming.
- So, how long were you in Santa Fe?
- Uh, just a year.
I started out CBI, made the jump
to the federal side
- about the same time as Cho.
- And he's worked with Jane before.
- Enough to know the score.
- And what's that?
He'll never tell you what he's up to.
Whatever he does,
you'll look like an idiot.
And always keep your hand
on your wallet.
Well, you do know the man.
I appreciate you coming tonight.
This case is blowing up.
- I hear you have 10 bodies.
- Yeah, five were found buried
killed between two and nine months ago.
Two were killed in their car last week
Gabriel Osborne and his sister
a few days after that
- and the woman today.
- Wow. Any, uh, physical evidence?
Just the bullets...
they match
but we haven't been able
to trace 'em to a gun.
Tork, I heard you were here.
It's good to see you.
- You, too.
- Anything from the profilers?
Uh, they can't find any patterns
in the killings.
Uh, the first two victims were homeless men
the third was a prostitute.
The next ones
were foreign-exchange students
and then the couple in the car.
There's no consistency
in age, race, or gender.
I don't think this is about who he killed
so much as what he killed for.
Hey, Tork. Long time, no see.
Do you mean the blood
and the fingernails?
Well, fingernails not so much.
I think they're just a gruesome trophy.
But the blood he had to work for.
He must need it for something.
Did any of the other victims
have puncture wounds?
Uh, the recent ones, yes.
The buried victims, we couldn't tell.
The bodies had decomposed.
I think we can assume he's been taking
blood samples for some time.
- The question is why.
- There are some theories online.
The most popular theory
is that he's a vampire of some sort.
- Not sure if that's helpful.
- Well, maybe it is.
- Really?
- Well, he is stealing blood from a corpse.
He's gotta be doing something weird
with it.
So, he could be interested in the occult.
He believes in psychics.
That's why he went after Gabriel.
Talk to Austin PD,
see if they have anything
on local cults and nontraditional religions.
Ask Homeland Security if they have
anything useful in their databases.
Well, if he's interested in psychics
Jane should talk to him.
Uh... Not a psychic, dude.
No, but you can fake it, right?
We could feed you to the media
say that you can communicate
with the afterlife
using your spiritual whatever.
If he's really into that,
we can get him to show himself.
The Son of Sam killer sent letters to two
of the writers who wrote about him.
Hey, this kinda thing could really work.
Did I... say something wrong?
Yeah, the last time Jane tried
something like that
it didn't go well.
- Oh, the wife and kid.
- Yeah, the wife and kid.
Hey, uh, I meant to tell you
we got Gabriel's autopsy reports back.
He had oligodendrogliomas...
they're tiny, little tumors in the brain.
According to the coroner,
they can cause seizures
blackouts, or delusional episodes.
Poor kid. No wonder he thought
he was psychic.
There's no such thing as psychics.
No.
I shouldn't have said anything
about the ring. I'm sorry.
- Teresa, please.
- Really, look...
you do what you need to.
I'm okay, I swear.
We just got a call from Austin PD.
They think they have the serial killer.
- Did they arrest him?
- The call said somebody shot him.
- This does not seem right.
- It's a false alarm.
A case of mistaken identity.
This is Sharon Nieto, Austin Homicide.
The dead man is Le Kong Vinh.
According to the neighbors
he goes around collecting recyclables.
The homeowner was asleep
when he heard banging
on the side of the house.
It was Mr. Vinh going through
his garbage
but he didn't know that.
He thought somebody was trying
to break in so he grabs his trusty .38.
Homeowner issued a challenge
through the door.
- Just heard more banging.
- And Vinh didn't speak English.
That's right.
So he fires through the door, calls us
says he shot a serial killer.
- Is that the victim's wife?
- Yeah.
I guess they were collecting
the bottles together.
Are you guys gonna catch
this whack job anytime soon?
People are freaked out.
We're getting calls all day.
Is your department logging
all the calls?
- Sure.
- Then we need that log.
Ah, it's a tough situation.
The city is in a full-on panic,
and we have no solid leads.
Okay, well, uh...
- Do we try Tork's idea?
- What? No.
I don't think that we can rule
anything out.
Boss.
The guy is not hiding bodies anymore.
You know, maybe he's starting to...
to like the attention.
Do you want him to do to Jane
what he did to Gabriel?
Now, you know
we won't let that happen.
- You can't promise that!
- Y-you know what?
I appreciate your spirited defense but it...
it's not necessary.
I'll do it.
Okay.
"According to state forestry officials"
"once the bear was tranquilized"
"he was relocated to a wilderness area."
"And now an update
from our AccuWeather desk."
I'm gonna say this one last time.
You don't have to do this.
I know that.
Coming up, a psychic
who's working with the FBI.
You're watching Austin Today.
Stay with us.
We're out. Back in 60.
Oh, you've done this before?
Yep.
All right, I'm gonna throw you
a couple easy questions
we'll have some fun,
just keep the ball in the air.
- Sure.
- "Back in 10."
5, 4, 3...
"Welcome back to Austin Today.
I'm Dan Glover."
"And with me is Patrick Jane
a psychic who works with the FBI."
I'd like to talk about how you're helping
to hunt
for the man
who's believed to have murdered
a number of our local citizens
but first I have to ask...
What is a psychic?
What is it you do?
Patrick?
- Patrick?
- Yeah, Dan, sorry, I was distracted.
Um, there's something on your mind.
Your wife, uh... just had a baby...
a girl, I believe.
- Who told you that?
- You did.
Uh, her, her name begins
with a vowel, A, E, A...
Alexa, uh...
Alexa, right?
That's... right.
- So that's how you do it, huh?
- That's how I do it, Dan.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
Your aunt...
passed away about a-a year ago.
18 months.
She used to help people.
- She was a teacher, I think.
- Yes.
Well, a counselor.
We didn't tell him any of this,
swear to God.
She really wants you to be happy
because she loves you...
very much.
That's it.
I-I can't tell you how uncanny this is.
I-I'm shivering.
So, tell us about this case
you're working on with the FBI.
"I'm not a detective.
I don't do police work."
I'm just trying to help my colleagues
understand this man.
"How would you describe him?"
"Well, cautiously, I would say
that he's obviously angry"
probably in a lot of pain
but I think he's trying to get in touch
with someone from the other side.
What makes you say that?
Who isn't?
We have a call from Anna Marie
in Pflugerville.
"Anna Marie, what's your question?"
- Hey.
- "Hi."
What's up?
Uh, Abbott sent me.
You can get outta here.
- I'll take Jane home when he's done.
- Oh, no, I'm okay.
No, forget it. You're beat. Go home.
All right.
"14 months ago. It was shortly after my
mother died."
"Well, I was at home alone,
and I went into the room where my..."
We have another call here from...
Lazarus, welcome to the show.
Lazarus. Interesting name.
"He rose from the dead."
So I hear.
What's your question, Lazarus?
"What else do you know
about the man the FBI is hunting?"
Well, I can't tell you everything
I know.
- "Why not?"
- Well, it's an ongoing investigation.
The case is still open.
Why are you interested?
Do you have information on the man?
- "You're the one who knows everything."
- I never said that.
"No, but you claim to be
in contact with his spirit."
- Boss, you hearing this?
- Yes, we are.
Wylie, how long until you trace
the call?
I'm gonna need another minute.
Make sure Jane keeps him
talking, okay?
"If you're not, why would the police
want your help?"
I get the feeling that you know more
about this case than you're saying.
If that's so, you should probably share.
"Why?"
So we can catch him.
"What if I don't want him caught?"
Oh, why would you feel that way?
"I spoke to someone like you
once before."
Really? Who?
"He was a complete fake."
"You could practically see it
written on him."
We didn't release
what was written on Gabriel's body.
Nobody knows that except us
and the killer.
That's our guy.
Uh, what's that address?
- Hmm, interesting.
- What?
He's not calling from a cellphone.
He's calling from a landline...
normal phone.
- Okay, that's the address, right?
- Yeah.
Call downstairs. We need backup.
When we left, you suggested
that you dealt
with another psychic
who wasn't on the up-and-up.
Are you a skeptic now?
"No, I believe in spirits very much"
"just not everybody who claims
to be in touch with them."
Any spirits in particular?
"You tell me. Who haunts you?"
Me? Uh, nobody.
"There must be spirits in your life."
Well, fortunately,
they leave me alone.
You still haven't told me whose spirit
you're trying to connect with.
- "Have to go now. Bye."
- Hold on.
Lazarus?
Hello?
Seems the caller has gone.
We're gonna take a minute
for a station ID.
We'll be right back
with Night Talk on KPQC.
Abbott, what's happening?
Something's wrong. He's not here.
He rigged the phone.
We don't know where he is.
"I don't know what he's doing,
but I don't like it."
You and Tork get out of there
and head back to the office.
- "We'll meet you there."
- Okay.
- Cho called. He said...
- Yeah, I heard. Let's go.
Hey, we're doing a show.
Hey!
What happened to you?
I was listening. You got caught off.
Yeah, the call was a ruse.
He's planning something.
"You need to get back
to the office as soon as you can."
Did you leave the door
of the Airstream open this morning?
No. Maybe.
W-why?
- It's open.
- "Okay, stop."
Don't go anywhere near it.
Don't do anything
until someone else gets there.
That could take forever.
I'm gonna check it out.
Yeah, fine, but you're not hanging up.
Jane. We have to go.
Just...
Jane.
Teresa, what's going on?
There's nobody in here.
I guess we left it open.
- Okay, get back to the office.
- All right, I'll see you there.
Let's go.
"Thank you for coming in."
An hour and a half ago
two agents were attacked by a man
who we believe is responsible
for 10 murders in the past year.
This man.
Agent Richard Tork is in the hospital.
I've been told that he's gonna be all right.
Patrick Jane, however,
has been abducted by this man
and is still being held.
So as of right now, no one goes home.
No one takes a nap or a coffee break
until Patrick Jane is returned
and this man is arrested.
Agent Cho will have your assignments.
We found the truck parked
a few blocks away.
We assume the suspect
switched vehicles.
All right, we need a team to sweep
security and traffic cameras in the area.
Elias, that's yours.
We also need fingerprint and DNA
evidence from the truck. Merrick.
You warned me.
I didn't listen, and I am sorry.
He could've killed Jane,
but he took him
so that means he wants something
and there is no one better at exploiting
a situation like that than Jane.
I hope you're right.
Water?
- No, thanks.
- Suit yourself.
You know who I am?
- Lazarus.
- That's right.
You expect me to call you that?
Don't be funny.
Well, you're the one that came up
with the name.
Interesting place.
Could do with a little update.
I saw you on TV.
You said you know things...
hear things.
Prove it.
It doesn't work like that.
You did it on TV.
Different circumstances.
You can't just...
you can't just make it happen.
The other one said something like that.
- You know who I mean?
- Sure.
So, I tested him.
He was a liar. Are you a liar?
No.
Prove it.
- Hi.
- Tork, please, go home.
- I'm okay.
- This isn't your fault.
Any of us had been there,
same thing would've happened.
Yeah, but... I was there.
I'll be at my desk.
- I might have something.
- What?
Jane said the killer was probably
doing something weird
with the blood he took, right?
So, I've been looking into local black
magic and occult connections.
- Find anything?
- Too much.
It's hard to find someone
who doesn't sound like a serial killer.
But one place keeps cropping up...
a bookstore called The Grimoire.
- The Grim, what?
- Grimoire. It's a magical textbook.
Yeah, a lot of people interested
in the stuff go there.
Maybe the killer did, too.
It seemed worth checking it.
It's only three miles
from where the bodies were buried.
Wylie, most of Austin is three miles
We appreciate the effort,
but it sounds thin
and we don't have the time to waste.
Jane would go.
He'd say, "Do the usual thing,
you get the usual result."
Which, in this case, is him dead.
Okay, Wylie. Let's go check it out.
This is your father's house, not yours.
A spirit tell you that?
No, the furniture.
Your mother died
when you were very young.
You were raised by your father.
He was strict...
But you feel now that you deserved it.
- He was right to punish you.
- Who's telling you that?
It's what I'm getting from you.
What else?
You didn't have any friends
when you were a kid.
You usually ate alone
not because people
wouldn't sit with you
but because you were disgusted
by the sounds they made when they ate.
Sometimes, other people
don't feel real to you.
They're like robots
wearing human skin.
What do I do for a living?
You're an exterminator.
Yet, again, it doesn't feel real.
It's like a movie being projected
on a screen.
That's impressive.
Thank you.
But I don't need to know about me.
I want contact with another.
I don't sense any spirits here.
You're wrong. The spirit is here.
If you don't know that,
then you're a fraud.
- No, I'm not.
- Just the like the other one.
- I'm not a fraud.
- You're a liar and a cheat.
You take it easy.
Hello?
No, ma'am. The job's finished.
No. No, it's...
Okay.
I'll address that. I'll be right over.
I'll be back.
- Hey.
- What?
Uh, I could...
I could use that water.
Thank you.
- Kelis Weir?
- Kee-lis, yes?
We're with the FBI.
Forget it. I'm not collaborating
with religious persecutors.
- What persecutors?
- We just wanna ask some questions.
You say that, then you start in
with your western morality.
Not fooling me twice.
What do you mean?
A while back, some guy
comes in, starts...
asking about Santeria.
I tell him some friends
are performing a ritual.
Oh, he shows up...
with 10 cops, arrests everybody
for animal abuse.
- Animal abuse?
- People cut up a million chickens a day.
They put testicle-sized chunks
in a fryer, call it commerce.
My friends...
use one for an ancient
and sacred ritual
and I go to jail?
Hey, you're just all a bunch
of Judeo-Christian jackbooted thugs
- as far as I'm concerned.
- Wylie, this is a waste of time.
Hold on, hold on, hold on.
Kelis has a point.
- She was duped. That isn't fair.
- Yeah.
- So?
- So, maybe we can help you.
How?
If you talk to us, just answer
some questions
we'll lean on Austin PD to reduce
your charges, maybe drop 'em.
Why would they do that?
The serial-killer case we're working on
the mayor, Austin PD...
they want him in custody fast.
If you help us make the arrest,
they'll owe us
and we can use that to help you.
He's right.
What do you wanna know?
We're looking for someone
who uses blood.
A lotta people do that.
What kinda blood?
Human blood.
Okay, that's different.
Those people do not come in here.
I'm a little too vanilla for them.
- Where do they go?
- The web mostly.
There's a site called Blackmore.
Hardcores, they go there.
I've been looking.
I haven't found that one.
That's because you gotta go
deep web.
You can't even find the site
without the IP.
Can you give that to us?
You're really gonna talk to Austin PD?
You're really gonna help me?
Yes.
Give me a minute.
It's not bad, huh?
The Blackmore site is huge.
It's the eBay of the deeply weird.
There are sections
on vampirism, self-vivisection...
- Self-vivisection?
- Yeah.
- Cutting yourself open.
- Okay.
How does this help us find Jane?
Well... there's also a section
on blood sorcery...
Magical things you can do with blood.
Now, you're supposed to use
your own blood, but...
15 months ago, there was a discussion
on harvesting blood from other people.
About 20 people were involved.
Why would you harvest blood?
Because you needed a lot.
15 months ago...
that was right around the time
our guy made his first kill.
He could be one of those people.
Can we get their names?
Well the screen names they used
are all super protected.
However, I was able to dig one out...
A guy named Alan Saltonstall.
A college professor in San Marcos.
- Let's go pick him up.
- Sure.
- What do they do with the blood?
- A couple of things
but the one that gets the most discussion
is a ritual that binds a spirit.
- Bind. How?
- If you have a corpse
you can bind the spirit of a dead person
by giving blood to their body.
That way, the spirit never leaves.
- Where are we with the search warrant?
- It's on its way to the judge right now.
- Is that Saltonstall?
- Yeah.
Well, why isn't somebody
talking to him?
He requested an attorney.
He's on his way now.
This guy could be torturing
Jane right now.
- We don't have time for this.
- I'm sorry, Lisbon.
- Let me talk to him.
- Look, the guy's lawyering up.
Let me talk to him.
Okay.
I already told him I won't say anything
without my lawyer present.
I don't care.
You're hiding something.
What?
I never would've noticed something
like this before
but I've been working
for a very long time
with somebody who's good
at seeing into people
what they're thinking, feeling.
I can tell there's something
you're worried
we're gonna find out about you.
That's ridiculous!
I'm guessing it has something
to do with the black magic
something violent or sexual,
maybe both.
But judging by how freaked out
you are
I'd say it's something really bad.
I am not freaked out.
And my interests such as
they are, are purely academic.
- I don't know what you think you're doing
- Shut up.
"I don't care what kinda
kinky stuff you're in to."
I have a friend who's in danger
and maybe you can help save him.
It's possible he's being held
by somebody
from that blood group of yours.
I want their names.
I don't know any names.
It's an online community, and...
I shouldn't even be talking to you.
You're lying. I can tell.
You have names.
You've met them, some of them.
I don't think you understand
how important this is to me.
You give me a name, you can walk
out that door right now.
You don't, and I will dig up
every dirty secret you have!
- You'll what?
- I will tell everybody you know...
your co-workers, your friends,
your family.
You are not gonna be able to hide!
Y-you're threatening me?
It's not a threat.
It's a promise.
You-you can't! That's...
that's illegal.
My boss is right back there.
Tell him.
Get me fired. Ruin my career.
I don't care.
I want those names.
He gave me eight names.
He says he can't remember the rest.
- Good work.
- How do we know he's not the killer?
We checked
his credit-card statements.
He was outta the country
for two of the murders.
Okay, we'll go out in pairs,
and I'll text you the names.
Track 'em down. See if they're connected
to the killings.
If you find a live one
let the rest of the team know fast.
Joe.
He's here, your father.
Big Joe.
That's who you wanna get
in touch with, right?
He says thank you for keeping him
for taking care of him.
The passing over was hard,
but now he's good.
His back doesn't hurt anymore.
He feels better now than he ever did
when Dr. Hannigan was feeding him
his meds.
- There's doubt in you.
- No.
- I-I mean...
- Put it aside. If...
if you doubt, then I lose
the connection with him.
I won't be able to communicate
with him.
Okay.
He says there's a lake...
- A lake Rickasee?
- Pickasee.
Pickasee.
He didn't catch a fish that day.
No.
No, you...
you caught a fish, a small one.
Daddy.
He wants to know
why you're keeping him here.
There's something in me...
a voice.
And when it starts, I can't ignore it.
I can't think about anything else
until I go out...
find someone...
And then it goes away again.
For a while.
Is that your voice, Daddy?
Is that you in me?
Are you sending me out?
Am I doing this for you?
- He's saying something.
- What?
Like...
It's not clear.
- It's not.
- No?
Yeah, I'm so...
I'm-I'm sorry. I...
He's...
He's gone.
Get him back.
I can't. I need...
I need...
- An hour.
- Get him back.
I need an hour. I just, I need to...
I need to rest.
This is how this works.
Hey, can I have some
of that gum, please?
Thank you.
We're looking for a man
named Joseph Keller Junior.
According to our records,
his last known address
was in an apartment building
that you manage, Ms. Martinez.
- But then he moved out.
- Yeah, Keller, weird guy.
Yeah, I think he moved
like two years ago.
- Did he leave a forwarding address?
- No.
I think he said something
about his dad being sick.
Can you remember anything else
about him, where he worked?
Some exterminator company.
Do you know the name
of the company or the address?
Maybe...
I think he sent me an e-mail about it
wanted me to hire him.
You want me to look for it?
- That would be wonderful, thank you.
- Okay.
I know it's in here.
While you're looking for that
we're just gonna step outside.
Okay.
- Any news?
- Not yet, sorry.
But I did find out something weird
about Keller.
What?
Not Keller Junior, but his father,
Joseph Keller Senior.
15 years ago, there was a string
of killings in the area.
Local PD took a hard look
at Keller Senior.
Really liked him for them
but they only had a circumstantial case
never found any conclusive
physical evidence.
Keller's father was a serial killer.
- Sounds like it.
- What happened to him?
I don't know. Case went cold.
Two or three years ago, he falls off
the map.
He had a house not too far outta town,
near Lake Pickasee.
You check out the house.
I'll wait until she finds a work address
and head over there.
Good.
It's been an hour.
- He's here.
- He, what?
He came back when you were gone.
He wants to talk to you.
He's in there.
- He wants to talk to me?
- That's right.
If you want answers,
they're in that room.
You can go in or not.
It's up to you.
Do you smell gas?
No.
"Jane?"
"Jane, are you in here?"
Jane?
Are you here?
Jane. Hey.
Can you stand up?
Come on. Let's get you up.
Oh, I got you.
Come on.
Don't you ever do that
to me again, ever.
And sign here...
and here...
- And here...
- There.
- And here. Yeah. That's it.
- Okay.
It's all yours.
Now, usually this is where
I hand over the keys
but there aren't any.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
- Thank you so much.
- You're very welcome.
- Bye.
- Bye-bye.
"Previously on The Mentalist..."
- "He says his name is Patrick Jane."
- Never met him.
- Did he say why he came in?
- Just that he wants to talk to you.
Mr. Jane!
"Teresa Lisbon, it's nice to meet you."
We always thought that you and Lisbon
would, you know, get together.
Jane and Lisbon, yeah right.
- And voila.
- So you're gonna build us a house?
- It's a start.
- I need to know
- that you're committed to this, to us.
- I am.
Then are you gonna take off
your wedding ring?
I have a guy who's saying things
about the murders.
- Well, what is he saying Wylie?
- He's a psychic.
I saw that the killer's gonna
kill again, tonight.
"Why would the killer care
if Gabriel was a real psychic?"
"He wants one for some reason
and Gabriel didn't pass the test."
"Welcome back to Austin Today.
I'm Dan Glover."
"And with me is Patrick Jane,
a psychic who works with the FBI."
I'm just trying to help my colleagues
understand this man.
- "How would you describe him?"
- "I would say that he's obviously angry"
"probably in a lot of pain."
Lazarus. Interesting name.
- "He rose from the dead."
- So I hear.
I saw you on TV.
You said you know things.
He's in there.
Jane... Hey.
Can you stand up?
- You Agent Tork?
- Yeah.
You guys done looking around in there?
'Cause we're just sitting
on our hands out here.
There's nothing we could find.
It's a mess in there.
But the structure's sound.
Your people can go in. Have fun.
Thanks.
All right, listen up.
It's been reported there are two bodies
in the basement of this house.
There may also be evidence
pertaining to as many as 10 homicides
committed by the recently deceased
individual known as Lazarus.
Real name Joseph Keller.
We wanna put these cases to bed
so that means break out
the fine-toothed combs.
Let's go.
How's your head?
- Oh, hey.
- Hi.
It's fine.
Ears are still ringing a little
but, uh...
just getting ready for the remodel.
- I brought sandwiches.
- Those are the magic words.
Come with me.
Is it me, or does it seem like
the house slants a little bit to the left?
Optical illusion.
You're not wearing
your wedding ring.
I'm not married.
The ground is slanty,
so it makes the structure
look like it's leaning,
but it is, in fact, not.
It's just an optical illusion.
- Slanty, huh?
- Yeah.
Technical term.
This ring has been with me
for a very long time, and, uh...
it has obvious significance
with my past.
It also represents...
meeting you.
If I didn't have this ring,
I would never have met you.
So in a sense, uh...
it has the potential to represent
my future, as well.
And I-I'm not expecting
you would ever wear it, but...
I wanna share it with you
and...
I want it to represent our future...
together.
I want you to be my wife.
Will you marry me?
Okay.
- Yes, yes.
- Yes?
Excellent.
I'm glad that's dealt with.
I was a little nervous.
Oh, come on. You knew
I was gonna say yes.
No, even after all these years,
you're still a mystery to me.
- I am?
- Thank you.
Hey, guys, how's the Lazarus case going?
Keller's house is being processed
right now.
Tork's on the scene.
We're just squaring away the paperwork.
Oh, good. Good, good, good.
All right.
Do you guys need anything? Can I help?
Mm... No, not really.
Look, you know, old job's over.
New job hasn't begun. You know,
I'm just spinning my wheels here.
- Hey.
- Hey, guys.
So, um... we wanted you
to be the first to know.
Um... yeah.
We're getting married.
Hey!
- I told you.
- No, you didn't.
- Congratulations.
- Oh, man!
- That's wonderful.
- That's awesome.
- Thank you.
- When's the big day?
Eh, no big day.
I don't want any wedding fuss.
Oh, we're just gonna slip away quietly
in the next couple of days.
All right.
"It's not unusual to be loved
by anyone"
"it's not unusual to have fun
with anyone"
"But when I see you
hanging around with anyone"
"It's not unusual to see me cry"
"I wanna die"
- "Hi. How are you?"
- "Good. How are you?"
"Good."
"But when I see you out
and about, it's such a crime"
"If you should ever wanna be
loved by anyone"
- Thank you. Have a nice day.
- Thank you.
"It's not unusual, it happens every day"
Oh, my lord. Sir?
I'm good.
That darn barbecue, I swear.
These are two for one, right?
- "Hey-hey! Hey!"
- "That's awesome!"
"Hey, even this guy's happy
about it, right?"
"Yeah, congrats."
- Oh, hi! Hey!
- "Hey."
- "Congratulations!"
- "Somebody went number two."
- Thanks.
- "Yeah. All right."
"So, anyway, did you tell uh--
did you tell Tommy yet?"
Eh, he's chasing a bail jumper
in Alaska.
I left him a message.
"Eh, well, you snooze, you lose."
"We're gonna miss him
at the bachelor party, though."
There is no bachelor party.
We're getting married
the day after tomorrow
just me and Jane
and the Justice of the Peace.
No big wedding, no guests.
"But... family, right?"
- "Yeah, family."
- "Yeah."
No, it's just us.
We wanna get married quietly.
"Well, so, we'll be quiet.
But we're gonna be there, T."
- "I mean, no argument."
- "Hey, Stan, hold it."
"It's her deal, her choice.
You know, she wants to do it that way"
- "then let her do it."
- "What are you saying, you mook?"
Guys, come on!
"If we're not there, Mom's gonna spin
in her grave"
- "like a freaking crankshaft."
- "Oh, my God."
"She'll be crying for shame
that our sister, our only sister--"
"Oh, would you can it, please, Stan?
Teresa just said she don't us there."
"Why would you wanna be there
if she doesn't want us there?"
- "I mean--"
- "You're a sad, bitter man, Jimmy Lisbon."
- "Well, I-I smile through it."
- "Don't you ever--"
- "I smile through the sadness."
- "Stop it. He's doing it again."
- "I got stronger, though."
- "Ever since he was a little kid--"
- "It's just-- it cuts to the airflow!"
- "Yeah."
- Don't worry.
- Don't worry about what?
You're worried that I'm gonna be upset
because you invited your brothers
to our marriage.
- How did you know that?
- When we're married
do you think you might stop
asking that question?
- It's okay, isn't it?
- They're family.
Thank you. It means a lot to them.
Of course.
Since my brothers are coming
it feels funny
not to invite just a couple
of members from the team.
No, no. You know what? You're right.
We should keep it small.
Small. Just my brothers.
Eh, fine. Invite away.
We're gonna need a few more guests
just to dilute the alcohol content.
- Thank you.
- Just three or four, though.
Where do we draw the line?
Well, that's why we decided
not to invite anyone.
I know. I know. I'm sorry. It's just--
here we are.
- Here we are.
- What?
Oh, look, I'm just gonna surrender
to fate, all right?
So be it.
Big, huge, massive wedding.
No, just 8 or 9 very close friends
at the courthouse-- 9 or 10
and then we can go
to O'Malley's bar afterwards.
12 tops.
Or we could go to a restaurant.
No big deal.
It's not like we're hiring a caterer.
- We don't have a gift registry or anything.
- Sure. Okay.
- Where are you going?
- Well, I have to get you a ring.
- I already have one.
- That is for us.
You need one for you.
- I do?
- You do.
All right, well, shouldn't I come
with you?
Isn't that how you're supposed
to do it?
No, I think we'll waste time bickering.
Besides, I have better taste.
- You think you do.
- You'll see.
- N-nothing too gauche.
- Bye!
- Hey, boss.
- Hey.
The less I have to do,
the more coffee I drink.
So, do you and Lena wanna come
and watch us get married?
Oh. Uh, Lena went to
a trade conference in Prague
but, uh, you know, I'd be honored.
I thought you guys
weren't having any guests.
Well, we kind of changed our minds.
It's just gonna be a few people--
a dozen, 15.
All right. I'm there.
Where and when?
We don't know yet.
It's nothing fancy.
Oh, well, you have to have it
at our house. I insist.
We have the perfect spot
for a casual wedding.
Really?
I'd be thrilled.
That is so nice of you.
- What's up?
- Some surprise, huh?
I didn't see the wedding thing coming.
It wasn't that hard to guess.
- Something on your mind?
- No.
Actually, yes.
Someone might get in touch with you
about me requesting a transfer.
I just wanted you to hear it
from me first.
- A transfer where?
- Salt Lake.
Office there is starting
a cyber-crime initiative.
They're looking for people.
It's desk work,
but it's more my speed, I think.
Uh, let's face it, I didn't do that well
when we were going after Keller.
It's not easy being in the bullpen.
Michelle's desk is right there, and...
Anyway, I think a change of pace
would be good.
Plus, you're gonna be rebuilding
the team.
This'll pretty much
give you a blank slate.
- Come here.
- What?
Come here.
- Stop feeling sorry for yourself.
- No, I'm not.
You are.
You made some mistakes going
after Keller? Welcome to the club.
I bat 300 on a good day.
You miss Vega.
Now remember who she was.
She'd never run away from a challenge
like this and neither should you.
And you're right.
I have to rebuild the team and I wanna
start with people that I know and trust.
- So stick around.
- Or what, you'll hit me again?
I'm asking you to stay, Wylie.
- Okay.
- Okay, good.
Check in with Tork.
I wanna know what's going on
at the house.
Sure. And Cho...
- Thanks.
- No problem.
This is the ring we sent you
a picture of.
It was my grandmother's.
Anne's dad gave it
to me to propose with.
Which is sweet, but it's not
really me, you know?
So we thought maybe we could
take the diamond out
put it in a necklace or something.
Of course. Uh, may I--
may I see it?
Oh, yeah.
Uh, let me get my loupe.
We'll just need to take
a closer look at the stone.
Excuse me, sir.
I'm helping another customer
right now, sir.
FBI--
give 'em back their ring right now
or I will be forced to shoot you.
Don't worry. Just kidding.
I don't even carry a real gun.
I have a lotta close friends
that do, though.
- What's happening?
- All will be revealed.
- Their ring is in your right hand.
- Uh, sir, you've made a mistake.
- We've got the ring right here.
- Uh, that's a replica.
A... replica?
He did a French drop to swap
the valuable ring with a cheap replica.
French drop is a sleight-of-hand move.
Not important.
That ring never belonged
to your grandmother
and it's not a real diamond.
- Is that true?
- Of course not.
He would study the ring
that he just gave you
then break the sad news that
your grandma's ring is a phony
and you'd be none the wiser.
This is insane.
Then you won't mind opening up
your right hand, will you?
Open up your right hand, please, sir.
Holy moly.
Well, thank you for your assistance, folks.
I'll take it from here.
Don't worry, ma'am.
The real ring is in your hand.
- Good day to you.
- Thank you.
My pleasure.
So, my crooked friend,
today is your lucky day.
- Is it?
- Well, on a normal day
you'd be off to the pokey now
but as it happens...
I'm in the market for a diamond ring.
So show me
your very best selection, please.
And, sir, if I see any glass...
the cuffs will come out.
Nothing too gauche.
What's up?
Tork just called in from the crime scene.
No intact corpses in the basement
but a lotta body parts,
badly burned and fragmented.
Have them rush the DNA tests.
Pull some strings if you have to.
Why the rush?
Still got a lotta media interest.
The bosses wanna be able
to announce we got the guy.
For that, we need a coroner's report,
so let's get on it.
Okay, right away.
- Hey, did Abbott give you the news?
- Hey.
We're having a real wedding
at his house.
- He did.
- You're gonna be there, right?
Of course.
I could use your help with something
if you're not too busy.
What's that?
What do you think?
Makes you look short.
Snow cone.
Slutty elf.
You want a simple piece
with clean lines
maybe something vintage
and off-white.
What he said.
Thank you for doing this.
I asked you along
'cause I thought you'd be honest.
I had no idea you were such
a fashion expert.
Not me.
My mom could run up
a designer gown before breakfast.
- Cut her cloth by eye.
- Cool.
My mom had a sewing machine,
but it was always in hock.
She'd be very proud of you.
Looking like this?
Very proud.
Thank you, Kimball.
All right, good night, Wade.
And, uh, tell Shaniqua
I said thanks for the fan mail.
Excuse me.
I-I don't have any change, man.
Hey, hey, hey!
Hey. Okay. Okay. Okay.
Here, look. You can take it.
You can take it. Here.
Get in the car.
Do as I say and you won't get hurt.
Stop the vehicle.
"Very slowly. No one gets hurt."
Put the car in park and get out.
Easy.
Give me your phone.
All right.
No problems.
What's the passcode?
There isn't any.
Wallet.
Look, uh, I only got
about 20 bucks in it.
And, uh...
Would you let me keep
my driver's license?
I-I don't wanna have to go
to the DMV.
Sure.
Here you go.
Thanks.
Thank you.
No! No! No!
- Tork.
- Patrick Jane, please.
Um, sorry. He's not in.
This is Dan Glover
from Austin Today.
I interviewed Jane recently
about this whole Lazarus case.
Sure. I remember you.
I just wanna do a quick follow-up.
Is he available?
I'm afraid, uh, you're gonna have
to wait a few days on that.
He's outta the office for a while.
Can you tell me where I can find him?
It'll only take a few moments.
I'd say he's pretty unfindable
at the moment.
"He's getting married in a few days."
- Married?
- Yeah.
I can, uh, take a message,
tell him you called.
No, no need.
Okey-doke.
Huh.
If I just remembered how tedious
this aspect of the marriage is
I might not have asked you.
No, seriously. I'm only on page two.
You know, I could just give you
the ring and we could elope.
Don't be mean. No take-backs.
I could give you this
and we could be in Fiji by nightfall.
There are people coming.
We're getting married, damn it.
- Suit yourself.
- You got a ring?
Yes, I did.
- You gonna show it to me?
- You wanna see it?
Show me.
I'll take this,
and you'll fill all of this out.
Oh, my God.
It's not real. You scared me.
- It's funny.
- Of course it's real.
- It's real?
- Real.
Oh, my--
Are you outta your mind?
You like it?
Well, it's gorgeous, but it's too much.
I-I can't accept it.
You can accept it, and you will.
It's yours. I want you to have it.
What is the Justice of the Peace's name?
Emily Hamilton.
- Oh, my...
- All right, let's file this sucker.
All right. We'll need confirmation
that the ceremony's been performed
within 72 hours, or you will need
to refile.
Congratulations.
- Who said romance is dead?
- I can't take this.
No, not yet you can't.
Well, at least let me try it on.
- Not yet.
- We don't even know if it fits!
- Lisbon, hi.
- Yes!
- Wylie, did we invite you yet?
- No, not yet.
Well, here it is.
Abbott's house, 12:00 Saturday.
But try not to spread it around.
We wanna keep it small.
And I don't wanna hurt
anybody's feelings.
I got you. Is there a gift registry?
- Uh, no gifts.
- Is there a trousseau?
- I don't know. What is that exactly?
- Never mind.
You're coming back
to work, right? Here?
Yeah, I think so.
- Why are you whispering?
- Lisbon, hey.
Someone's trying to reach you.
Oh, my God.
- "Hey, boss."
- "Hi."
- I'll talk to you guys later, okay?
- It is so good to see you guys.
"Right back at ya."
"Well, the news is spreading fast
through the CBI grapevine."
- "It's true, isn't it?"
- It's true.
"Oh, well, we had to call
and say congratulations."
"So, you and Jane, huh?
We always knew."
"We always knew?
I always knew."
How are the kids?
- "Uh, sticky, mostly."
- "The kids are great."
I know it's short notice, but you guys
have gotta come out for the wedding.
It's Saturday.
"Oh, my gosh, of course.
We'd love to."
"It will take a little child-care juggling
but we can swing it."
"You know, worst comes to worst
we'll just bring the little monkeys with us."
- "Keep 'em locked in the rental car."
- "Will not."
- "I'm kidding."
- "Mommy!"
"No, but seriously, we wouldn't
miss it for anything."
"I gotta go. We'll see you soon."
All right, I'll send you the details.
"Great. Take care."
Okay, you guys are all set. It should be
in the mail three to five days.
Thanks.
Excuse me. I need to fill out
a marriage license.
Um, usually there's two of you.
She's running late. I'll get started.
Okay, well, uh, paperwork
is in the end tray.
Just fill that out.
We need both of you here, plus ID.
I see.
Will do, thanks.
City Clerk's office. Please hold.
Thanks for holding.
Yes, how may I help you?
No, ma'am. You can't file online.
Until six, but we're closed
from twelve to one.
You're welcome.
Looks like she stood me up.
Bad omen for a wedding, huh?
Abbott.
Can I run something by you?
Yeah, shoot.
Spot DNA test came back
from the Keller house.
So far, all the recovered body parts
belong to Joe Senior, none for Junior.
They found his gun, but not him.
Oh, damn.
It could be that he was at the epicenter
of the explosion and was vaporized.
But there's a strong possibility
that Keller, A.K.A. Lazarus, is still alive.
Damn.
I let Austin PD know
and we're putting out a BOLO
to all the local hospitals.
Wylie's putting together a KA list
and I'm gonna have agents set up
shop at all of them.
- Well, did you put out a wire just in case--
- He runs for the border, yeah.
All right, well, it seems like
you have everything handled.
I don't know if I should tell
Jane and Lisbon.
- Good question.
- Yeah.
I wouldn't.
We don't have enough to be sure.
And, you know, they're
in a good space right now.
If Lisbon found out
that this case isn't closed
it's likely that she'll cancel the wedding
and join the hunt.
Yeah, there's plenty of time
to tell them after.
But, if he's still alive...
You know, Keller's unpredictable
and Jane did try to kill him.
You know, just in case
why don't we put some bodies
at the wedding
just to keep an eye out.
And it's my house,
so I'll arrange it.
You sure?
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
It's something to keep me busy.
Okay, thanks.
Abbott said it's totally up to you
but that you'd probably prefer
to hold the ceremony outside
and there isn't really
a room inside big enough.
Well, how many people
are we talking about?
Oh! A lotta people are talking about it.
Well, we only invited like 15 people.
Mm... more like 25 or--
I know.
And I don't think people
are waiting for, like a printed invitation...
seeing as there isn't one.
But, hey, on the plus side,
you're popular, girl!
Is that what all these tables are for?
Yeah, Abbott thought they'd be useful.
Don't worry.
He's covering the rental...
and the bartender...
and the caterer.
I guess they're his wedding gift.
I don't know.
Hey, here's a menu.
- There's a caterer?
- Yeah. Yeah, it's fine.
Abbott's loaded.
I mean, look at this house.
I think his wife cleaned up
in the private sector.
Wow.
"Here we are.
Hey, everybody out."
- Hey, Teresa!
- Hey!
- We're here!
- Hey-hey!
T!
Hi! Wow!
- You all came! So many people.
- Yeah, hey.
Sure we came.
We're gonna let our sister down?
- Congratulations.
- Thanks.
Yeah, hey, guys, say hi to your
Aunt Teresa, all right?
- Hi!
- Who is this?
- Oh, T, this is Lucy, my fiancée.
Lucy, Teresa.
I am so freaked out to meet you at last.
- We're gonna be sisters! Yay!
- Yay!
It's a long story.
- So, you're all here. Welcome to Austin.
- Thanks.
Yeah, it looks like we brought
the weather with us.
FBI!
- Sorry, I'm freaking out right now.
- Yeah, we got that.
- Excuse me?
- You all came.
- Yeah. Already said that, T.
- Let's go in!
- Jason! Jason! Come here!
- Yeah! Okay.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
Uh, excuse me, sir.
We have an odd coincidence...
Or not. Maybe.
Austin PD got a missing-person's report
on a local television reporter
named Dan Glover.
The one that interviewed Jane.
Yeah, left work Thursday night,
hasn't been seen since.
The weird thing is, he called here
right around the time he was last seen.
I spoke to him. He said
he wanted to interview Jane again
and I said he was unavailable
because he was getting...
married.
So, you're not even sure
if you spoke to Glover?
No, I mean, I was certain
at the time.
Obviously, it was his caller ID
but now--
So, we have to assume
the killer's alive and looking for Jane.
How many agents are you gonna have
at the wedding?
Four, but now I think
we should probably have more.
At least 10.
We're gonna need eyes
on the front and backyards
and the surrounding neighborhoods.
We should have a chopper on standby
in case we need to pursue.
Yes, sir.
But wouldn't it be wiser
to just postpone the wedding?
Postpone the wedding?
We're the FBI.
There is that upside.
We can use the wedding as bait...
kind of.
I'm gonna go check on that chopper.
Still think we shouldn't tell
Jane and Lisbon?
We're the FBI.
Just like you said, we can handle it.
Abbott.
Hey.
What were you and Cho and Tork
huddled about?
Nothing special.
Nothing special
that's keeping you here
when you could be in Prague
with your lovely wife?
You know, she doesn't need me around.
I...
I get in the way.
You're lying to me.
I won't pursue the point
because you would tell me
if it was something important.
Oh, yeah, yeah.
Yeah, of course.
If-if I thought that it was something
that we couldn't handle.
You know, um...
I've been getting some calls about you
and my bosses wanna know
if you're sticking around.
That's a good question.
All right, well, no pressure.
But if you're going
there is some legal stuff
that we need to handle
to expunge that deal that we made.
The napkin?
I'm getting married tomorrow.
Then I'm building a house, and...
beyond that
I genuinely have no idea.
And I can't do this job forever
but it's gonna be tough to give up.
Yeah, it's hard giving up
making a difference, huh?
No, everyone makes a difference.
- Hard to give up the chase.
- Oh, yeah.
That it is.
So, you, uh, let me know
when you know.
I will.
It has been very good
working with you, Patrick.
You too, Dennis.
I really appreciate your honesty.
I love you for that.
Thank you.
Okay, you got me. I was lying.
There is something
I need to talk to you about.
- Hey.
- Hi.
Nice flowers.
They're centerpieces.
- It's a Sylvan theme.
- Sylvan theme.
All right. Cool, I guess.
How many... people are
actually coming to this thing?
Nobody knows exactly.
Okay.
How did this happen?
This is not what I wanted.
Well, I like the Sylvan theme.
We should've just eloped
like you said.
- What about your family?
- Oh, they wouldn't care.
I just talked to them at the hotel.
They found a minibar.
They're like cavemen
arguing over a dead antelope.
All right, well, uh...
Let's run, huh?
We'll tell nobody, just the judge.
I'll have her meet us
at our little cabin tomorrow morning.
- The cabin?
- Just us.
What, you think the judge
would do that?
Well, sure. I mean, she's driving in
from San Antonio tonight.
Change of venue makes
no difference to her.
- Well, what about the witnesses?
- We'll get someone... Park ranger.
- You know what? Let's do it.
- Yeah.
- It's our life, damn it.
- Yes.
- I love you. Thank you.
- I love you, too.
- Hey, there's a--
- I'm gonna go get my dress
and I'm gonna go to the Airstream.
I'll meet you there.
Well, there's another very good reason
why we should elope, all right?
Keller is apparently still alive
and he's mad at me for some reason.
- Oh, my God.
- Yeah, so Cho and his people
are gonna stake out this house.
When Keller shows up, they'll nab him.
You were gonna withhold
this information from me?
You were gonna deprive me
of a guilt-free elopement?
- I just told you.
- You almost didn't!
From now on, we need to be
100% honest with each other.
- I agree with you 100%.
- Okay.
- Honesty.
- I am gonna go get my dress.
- Fire up the Airstream.
- You go, girl.
Hi. Judge Hamilton, Patrick Jane.
Uh, there's been a change of venue.
Okay. No problem, Mr. Jane.
If you just text me the exact address
and perhaps a decent motel nearby.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Great. Bye.
We got four agents on the roof
five dressed as catering and valet service
six on the perimeter
and six undercover mobiles
covering the approach roads.
When the guests get here
I'll gather them inside
and explain the situation.
Most of them are law enforcement
so they'll understand.
What is it, Wylie?
Office got a call off the BOLO
from a clerk
at the South Austin Registry Office.
A man with extensive burns
came in yesterday
and pretended to fill out a form.
The clerk thinks
he may have taken a peek
at the marriage-license forms
on her desk.
So that confirms it.
He is coming to the wedding.
Well, we got it covered.
Why are you so anxious, Wylie?
I know all the state forms from
when I used to work downtown.
The marriage-license form
doesn't ask where the wedding is.
- It just asks who the officiant is.
- Well, that's the judge.
Yeah.
- Hey, you.
- Hi.
Wow.
Well, no matter what happens,
from this point on
we have to promise each other that...
we will always
look on the bright side.
I promise.
Me too.
Freeze! Drop the gun!
And see how much better things turn out
when you're honest with me?
Thank you.
Let's do this.
No hard feelings.
Patrick, do you take Teresa to be
your lawful, wedded wife
to have and to hold
in sickness and health
for better or for worse,
till death do you part?
I sure do.
And, you, Teresa, do you take Patrick
to be your lawful, wedded husband
to have and to hold in sickness and health
for better or for worse,
till death do you part?
I do.
Then by the power granted me
by the State of Texas
I declare you husband and wife.
You may kiss the bride.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Patrick and Teresa.
"Do you remember"
"The 21st night of September?"
"Love was changing the minds
of pretenders"
- "While chasing the clouds away"
- Who else is gonna hug me? Come on!
"Our hearts were ringing"
"In the key that our souls were singing"
"As we danced in the night, remember"
"How the stars stole the night away?"
"Say, do you remember"
"Dancing in September?"
"Never was a cloudy day"
"My thoughts are with you"
"Holding hands with your heart
to see you"
"Only blue talk and love, remember"
"How we knew love was here to stay?"
"Now, December found the love..."
How you feeling?
I am so happy.
Me too.
There's something I need to tell you.
No, you're--
you're kidding me?
I'm not kidding.
You are?
I am.